

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211









Delivery Manager (IT and Embedded) seeking roles in Agile Project Management, Program Management, Service Delivery Management. Expertise in Healthcare and Storage domains, Product Engineering, Cloud Computing, Embedded Product Engineering



Total Experience: 24 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics]

Current Designation: Director (Delivery) -IT

Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services Ltd.,

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Director (Delivery), Program Manager, Agile Project Management, Program Management, Cloud Computing, IT Service Delivery Management, Embedded Product Engineering, TFS, JIRA, Rally, Live Link, MTM, Redmine, Clear Case, Clear Quest, C, C++, C#. Net, Java, SQL

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21

Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Over 24+ years of experience in Software and Embedded product engineering in various roles extending from RnD engineer, FW developer, Product Owner, Program manager to Account Manager

Strong 16+ years of Product Engineering experience in Medical devices and Healthcare practice

Proven 10+ years of Agile coaching experience in the areas of Kanban, Scrum, Lean-Agile, SAFe 5.0 and Agile Project

13+ years of extensive Agile Product Delivery Experience having successfully completed programs in cross functional product development environment with distributed teams

Proven professional skills in all phases of product and software development life cycle, right from ideation, scoping, project planning & scheduling, cost & efforts estimations, development, change management, system integration & testing, DevOps, quality measurements and EOL support

Work Experience

Capgemini Technology Services Ltd., as Director (Delivery) -IT Oct 2004 to Oct 2004

Aug 2011 - Present: Director (Delivery) Oct-2008 - July-2011: Program Manager Oct-2004 - Sep-2008: Project Manager

Digital Engineering and Manufacturing Services (DEMS) group

Technology Stack: C, C++, C#.Net, Java, SQL, Embedded systems, System Engineering, IoT, Cloud Computing (AWS) etc

Team Size: Ranging from 80 to 110 Overall Portfolio size: Ranging 6 to 8 Mn USD

Tools: TFS, JIRA, Rally, Live Link, MTM, Code collaborator, Redmine, Clear case, Clear Quest Test Automation tools: QTP/UFT, WinRunner, AscentialTest, TestComplete, Cognitive QA Tools

Major Accounts:

Lean-Agile and SAFe Portfolio Management

Japan based Global leader manufacturer of Class II Diagnostics Imaging products Global Diagnostic and Patient Monitoring medical devices manufacturing giant, in Europe US based Global Class III Cardiovascular devices manufacturing company

World leader in Storage devices manufacturing company in Japan and India captive

Customers are major giant, manufacturer of Class II medical devices like CT scan, MRI, X-Ray, Mobile surgery, PACS and other diagnostic imaging and Enterprise applications and products

The US customer is major Class III cardiovascular device manufacturer like pacemakers, ICD, IVDs

Executed various types of projects like development of core functionalities, enhancements, migration, porting, platform sustenance, escalation incidence management

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Worked on various sub-systems like Host, Recon, post processing, filtrations, Voice recording, CAN protocol implementation, service tools, Raw Data, Image processing tools, Remote monitoring systems and many more Various Programs on HW, FW and mechatronics like Product Re-engineering, HW Test fixture design, Mechanical design, compliance &certifications, Prototyping &production support, System engineering etc.

Enabled documentation support for FDA regulatory submission.

Medical domain perspective: Worked in areas like imagine processing, image viewers, DICOM, HL7, HIPAA compliance, IHE Profiles implementations, MDR etc.

Managed Projects leveraging various business models like outcome based, Fix Price as well as T&M model, in Agile and SAFe framework

Product VnV projects in the areas of Cognitive QA (CQA), Test Automation, Refactoring etc.

Software deliveries using Agile and SAFe frameworks.

Responsibilities:

Reporting to Business heads and leadership team on strategic planning, business analysis and portfolio management for product lines with their fund allocations. Also, full ownership of account management, its vision, roadmap and financial targets

Accountable for overall execution and successful program deliveries. Responsible for program and project planning, change management, costing, resourcing, budget planning etc. Managing direct reports across multiple Scrum teams and time zones

Being a Product Owner and in Product Management team, responsible for finalizing SRS, PI planning, Iterations/User stories acceptance etc.

As a SAFe change agent, responsible for implementation of SAFe framework and Agile practice at business vertical level; started with small teams, achieved short wins and then scaled it to account and business vertical level Trained project managers and leaders on Lean-Agile and SAFe culture in the teams. These leaders then percolated Agile and SAFe practice further to the teams and other stakeholders

Single Point of Contact for all stakeholders like project teams, customer, third party vendors, RnD practice group, quality management team to accomplish business goals and targets

Responsible for achieving delivery as well as financial goals & targets like productivity & quality improvements, innovations, margins, GOP, DVI and other KPIs

Lead delivery excellence, process standardization and optimization initiatives to improve productivity, time to market and achieving cost efficiency

Proactively proposed and successfully implemented cost efficiency ideas in the process, methodologies, product and people related areas.

Capgemini Technology Services Ltd., as Director (Delivery) -IT

Oct 2004 to Till Date

- 1. Agile Program Delivery Management
- 2. Healthcare (Medical Devices) and Storage domain programs.
- 4. Embedded and Systems Engineering programs
- 4. SAFe and Agile coach and training

Nelco Ltd. as RnD Engineer

Apr 1999 to Sep 2004

Major Projects:

3 Phase Traction Motor development for Indian railways (TOT from ABB) Intrusion Detection system for Indian Defense forces

Plant Automation of Automatic Gauge Control System (AGC) for Steel Plant

Technology

Embedded System Design with HW development on Microprocessors, ASIC, DSP etc.

Firmware development on VRTX and VxWorks RTOS

Control Panels development and testing for gas monitoring and other data acquisition systems

Responsibilities:

Having responsibility to develop and commission first batch of product at customer place.

Prepare set-up required for system and product testing, production plan.

Prepare test jigs, HW and SW simulators for module as well as integration & system level testing

Digital Electronics Ltd. as Senior Engineer

Nov 1997 to Mar 1999

Major Projects: Enhancements and Testing of Products like Printers, Plotters, Strip chart Recorders

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics) from Shivaji University, Maharasthra in 1994

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Version Last Used	Experience
	Version Last Used

Java, SQL

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Japanese				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.